the following content is provided under a Creative Commons license
以下内容是根据Creative Commons授权提供
your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue to offer
您的支持将有助于麻省理工学院开放式课程继续报价
high-quality educational resources for free
免费优质教育资源
to make a donation or view additional materials from hundreds of them IT
进行捐赠或查看附加材料由数百人资讯
courses
课程
visit MIT OpenCourseWare at 0 CW
参观麻省理工学院开放式课程在0 CW
that MIT ided you
麻省理工学院被提供的你
ha
the norm
规范
are
有
over the past several lectures we've developed the representation for linear
在过去的几次讲座，我们已经开发了代表的线性
time-invariant systems
时不变系统
in a particularly important center systems
在一个特别重要的中心系统
which are linear and time-invariant are those that are represented by linear
这是线性时不变的是那些由线性表示
constant coefficient differential equations continuous-time
连续时间常系数微分方程
or when your constant coefficient difference equations
或者当你常系数差分方程
in discrete-time for example electrical circuits that are built let's say I dove
在离散时间，例如内置的电路比方说，我的鸽子
resistors inductors and capacitors perhaps with %ah pants
电阻，电感和电容也许％啊裤子
correspond to systems described by differential equations
对应于由微分方程描述的系统
mechanical systems with springs and dash pots likewise
力学系统的弹簧和破折号同样盆
are described by differential equations and in the discrete-time
通过微分方程，并在离散时间中描述
case things such as moving average filters
万一事情，例如移动平均滤波器
digital filters and most simple kinda data smoothing
数字滤波器和最简单的还挺数据平滑
are all linear constant coefficient difference equations
都是线性常系数差分方程
now presumably
现在想必
in a previous course you've had some exposure to
在以前的你当然已经有一些接触
differential equations for continuous-time and
在连续时间和微分方程
their solution using notions like particular solution and homogeneous
像使用特定的解决方案，并均匀概念及其解决方案
solution initial conditions center
解决方案的初始条件中心
later on in the course
后来在使用过程中
when we've developed the concept to the 48 transforming after that the
当我们开发的理念，以48转化后的
apostrophe its form
撇号的形式
will see some very efficient and useful ways
会看到一些非常有效和有用的方式
generating solutions both differential and difference equations
生成解决方案的微分与差分方程
at this point however I'd like to
在这一点不过，我想
just introduce when your constant coefficient
刚引进时，你常系数
differential equations and the discrete-time counterpart
微分方程和离散时间对应
and address among other things the issue
及（其中包括）解决问题
love when they do and don't correspond to linear time-invariant systems
谈恋爱的时候，他们做的和不符合线性时不变系统
well let's first consider
那么让我们先考虑
what I refer to as an nth order
我指的是一个n阶
linear constant coefficients differential equation as i've indicated
正如我指出线性常系数微分方程
here
这里
and what it consists of is a linear combination of derivatives up the system
和它所包含的衍生物组成系统的线性组合
output
产量
y'at equal to a linear combination
y'at等于线性组合
of derivatives above the system input accept T
衍生品以上系统的输入接受Ŧ
and is referred to
并且被称为
as a constant coefficients equation of course because the
当然，作为一个常系数方程，因为
coefficients are constant in other words not assume to be time-varying
系数是常数，换句话说不假定为随时间变化的
and its referred to
及其简称
as linear because it corresponds to a linear combination
为线性的，因为它对应于一个线性组合
love these derivatives not because
喜欢这些衍生物不是因为
it corresponds to a linear system and in fact
它对应于一个线性系统，实际上
as we'll see or as all indicate this
正如我们将看到或都表明这
equation may or may not in fact correspond to
公式可能会或可能不会在实际上对应
when your system in the discrete-time case
当你的系统在离散时间情况
the corresponding equation is a linear constant coefficient difference equation
相应的方程是线性常系数差分方程
and that corresponds to again
和对应于再
a linear combination love the late versions of the output equal to
线性组合爱的输出等于后期版本
a linear combination love the late versions at the input
线性组合爱晚版本在输入
this equation is referred to as an nth order
这个方程被称为第n阶
difference equation the N referring to the number of the ladies
差分方程N个指的是女士们的数
are the output involved just as an aunt order differential equation
涉及就像一个阿姨阶微分方程的输出
the N for the order the equation refers to the number of derivatives
N个的订货公式是指衍生工具的数量
the output now let's first begin
输出现在让我们先开始
with the near constant coefficient differential equations
与附近常系数微分方程
and the basic
和基本
point or the solution for
点或为溶液
the differential equations is the fact dead
微分方程的是死了
if we've generated some solution
如果我们已经产生了一些解决方案
which I refer to here's why superiority some solution
而我指的是这里的原因优越性一些解决方案
to the equation for a given input then
等式对给定的输入，然后
in fact we can and to that solution
其实我们可以和该解决方案
any other solution which
任何其他的解决方案，
satisfies what's referred to as
满足什么的简称
the homogeneous equation so in fact
齐次方程，实际上
this differential equation by itself
本身这个微分方程
is not a unique specification
不是一个独特的规格
the system
系统
if I have any solution then I can
如果我有任何的解决方案，然后我可以
and to that solution any other solution which satisfies the homogeneous equation
并且该解决方案的任何其他解决方案，满足齐次方程
and thus all those two
因此，所有这两个
likewise be a solution and that's very straight forward to verify
同样是一个解决方案，这是非常简单的验证
by simply substituting into the differential equation
通过简单的代入微分方程
some love the particular a particular and the homogeneous solution
有些爱特别是特定和均相溶液
and what you see is that the homogeneous contribution
而你看到的是，均匀的贡献
in fact goes to zero by definition
实际上变为零的定义
what we mean by the homogeneous equation now
我们所说的齐次方程的意思是现在
the homogeneous solution for a when your constant coefficient differential
一，当你常系数微分方程的齐次解
equation
方程
is of the form that I
的形式为我
indicate at the bottom and
表明在底部和
it typically consists love a
它通常由一个爱
song or capital and complex exponentials
歌曲或资本和复指数
and the Constance
和康斯坦斯
are on determined by the equation itself
是由上述方程本身确定
and this form for the homogeneous solution
而这种形式的齐次解
in essence drops out love examining
在本质上滴出爱情审查
the homogeneous equation where
齐次方程，其中
if we assume that the former the homogeneous solution
如果我们假设前者的均匀溶液
is a complex exponential with some
是一个复指数的一​​些
on specified amplitude and unspecified exponent
在指定的幅度和不确定指数
if we substitute this into are homogeneous equation
如果我们这代成是齐次方程
we end up with the equation that i've indicated
我们最终的方程式，我已经指出
year the factor A&E the st. can in fact be
今年因子A＆E的ST。其实也可以
cancelled out and we find there that equation
取消了，我们发现那里的公式
is satisfied
纳
for capital N values
资本N个值
love s and
爱s和
that's true no matter what choices made for these
这是真的，不管选择什么为这些
coefficients and the essential consequence
系数和必不可少的后果
have all of that is that the homogeneous solution
有所有这一切是均匀的溶液
is of the form that I indicated previously
就是我前面所指出的表格
namely it consists love some
即它是由一些爱
love capital and complex exponentials
爱资本和复指数
where the coefficients the capital and coefficients
其中系数的资本和系数
attached to you to those complex exponentials
连接到您的复指数
is undetermined Iran specified
是不确定的伊朗指定
so what this says is that in order to
所以这是什么说的是，为了
obtain the solution for a win here comes the coefficient differential equation
获得一场胜利的解决方案来这里的系数微分方程
we need some kind of auxiliary information
我们需要某种形式的辅助信息
tells us how to obtain these capital and
告诉我们如何获得这些资金，
undetermined Constance and there are a variety of ways
未定博登和有各种不同的方式
specifying this auxiliary information or auxiliary conditions
指定该辅助信息或辅助条件
for example in addition to the differential equation
例如，除了微分方程
what I can tell you is the value
我可以告诉你的是价值
of the output and and -1 up there
输出和与-1那里的
and -1 if its derivatives at some
和-1，如果它的某些衍生物
specified time t0 and
指定的时间t0和
so the differential equations together
所以微分方程在一起
with the auxiliary information the initial conditions
与辅助信息的初始条件
van lets you determine the total solution
面包车让您决定整体解决方案
which namely lets you determine these previously unspecified
它即可以让你确定这些先前未指定
coefficients in the homogeneous solution
在均相溶液中的系数
now depending on how the auxiliary information is stated or what auxiliary
现在根据辅助信息是如何陈述或什么辅助
information is available
信息可用
the system a or may not correspond
该系统一个或可能不对应
to a linear system and may or may not correspond to a linear time-invariant
到一个线性系统，并且可能或可能不对应于一个线性时不变
system one essential condition
系统中的一个必要条件
for it to correspond to a linear system is that
它对应于一个线性系统是
the initial conditions must be zero
初始条件必须是零
and one can see the reason for that
人们可以看到，之所以
if we refer back to the previous lecture in which we saw that for a linear system
如果我们重提中，我们看到，对于一个线性系统前面的讲解
if we put 0n we get zero out
如果我们把0N我们得到了零
so if exit see the input is zero the output must be zero
因此，如果出口看的输入为零的输出必须是零
and so that in essence tells us that at least for the system to be linear
并使得在本质告诉我们，至少对于系统是线性的
these initial conditions must be zero
这些初始条件必须是零
now beyond that if
现在超越，如果
we want the system to be
我们希望该系统能
causal and linear time in and time-invariant
在和因果和线性时间时不变
then what's required on the
那么什么是需要的
initial conditions is that they be consistent with
初始条件是它们是一致
what's referred to as initial rest initial arrest says
什么是被称为初始静止初始逮捕称
that the output must be
该输出必须
0 up until the time
0直到时间
that the input becomes 90 and we can see
该输入变为90，我们可以看到
of course that that's consistent with the notion of causality as
当然了这是因果关系的概念是一致
we talked about in the previous lecture and
我们在前面的演讲谈到了和
its relatively straightforward to see
其相对简单的看
that if the system is causal and linear and time-invariant
如果系统是因果和线性和时间不变
that will require
这将需要
initial rest it's somewhat more difficult see
最初的休息是较为困难见
that if we specify initial rest the NAT in fact is sufficient to
如果我们指定初始静止实际上NAT是足以
determine that the system is both causal in linear
确定该系统既是因果的线性
and time very but the essential point then is that
和时间，但很重要的一点则是，
requires initial rest for both linearity
最初需要休息两个线性
and causality okay well
和因果关系也没关系
let's look at an example and
让我们来看一个例子，
let's take the example love a first-order
让我们的例子中爱一阶
differential equation as I've
差分方程，因为我已经
indicated here so we have
在这里表示，所以我们有
a first-order differential equation the wife TTT
一阶微分方程的妻子TTT
was a yote is the input exit
是一个yote是输入口
T and let's first
T和让我们先
look at what the homogeneous solution this equation is
看看这个公式是什么样的均相溶液
and so we can consider the homogeneous equation
所以我们可以考虑齐次方程
namely the equation specify solutions
即方程指定的解决方案
which would correspond to zero input
这将对应于零输入
we in essence guess for impose
我们在本质上猜测征收
a solution love the form the homogeneous solution
一个解决方案的爱的形式均匀的溶液
is an amplitude factor times the complex exponential
是振幅因子乘以复指数
substituting this into the homogeneous equation
代入的齐次方程
we then get the equation that i've indicated here
我们再拿到，我已经在这里指出的方程
what you can see is that this equates in this equation
你可以看到的是，这相当于在这个等式
I can cancel out the amplitude factor and this complex exponential
我可以取消的振幅因子和这个复杂的指数
so let's just cancel those out on both sides of the equation
所以我们只取消了那些对等式的两边
and what we're left with is an equation
而我们留下了什么是方程
that specifies what the complex exponent must be
用于指定复杂的指数必须是
in particular for the homogeneous solution s must be equal to minus a
特别是为均匀的溶液s必须等于减去一个
and so finally are homogeneous solution
所以最后是均相溶液
is as I've indicated year
是因为我已经表明今年
okay now let's look at the solution for specific input let's consider for
还好现在让我们来看看具体的输入解决方案，让我们考虑
example input
例如输入
which is a scale units step and
这是一个尺度单位工序和
although I won't work at the solution in detail and perhaps
虽然我不会在详细的解决方案的工作，也许
using what you've worked on previously
用你以前曾在
you know how to carry out the solution for that the
你知道如何进行该解决方案中的
a solution with step input
与阶跃输入的解决方案
is what i've indicated here scaler one minus the next financial times unit
就是我在这里表示分频器一减的未来金融时报单元
staff and you can verify that simply by substituting into the differential
工作人员和您可以验证通过简单的代入差分
equations now
现在方程
we know that there's a family of solutions in other words
我们知道，有一个系列解决方案，换句话说
any solution with
任何解决方案
a homogeneous solution added to it is again a solution
添加到它的均匀溶液再次是溶液
and so if we consider the solution I just indicated
所以，如果我们考虑解决方案，我只是指出
we generate the entire family of solutions by
我们通过生成解决方案的整个家庭
ending a homogeneous solution to it and so
结束了均匀的溶液，以它等
this then corresponds to the entire family of solutions
这则对应的解决方案的整个家庭
where the constant a is unspecified
其中常数a为未指定的
so far and needs to be specified through some type avoids avery conditions
到目前为止，需要通过某种类型的指定避免艾利条件
now a class A auxiliary conditions
现在是一个A类的辅助条件
is the Commissioner initial rest which
是初始专员其余的
as i indicated before is equivalent to the statement that the system
正如我之前等同于声明中指出，系统
is causal and linear and time-invariant and
是因果线性时不变和
in that case for the initial rest condition
在这种情况下，用于初始静止状态
we would then require in this equation above
那么我们就需要在这个等式以上
that this constant be equal to 0
这个常数等于0
and so finally the response
所以最后的响应
to scales step if the system
地磅秤步骤，如果系统
is the correspond to cause a linear time-invariant system
为对应于导致线性时不变系统
is then just this term namely
然后只是这个词即
constant times one minus an exponential
常数乘以一减指数
times step
次步
okay now if the system is a linear time-invariant system
现在没事了，如果系统是线性时不变系统
it can as we know be described through its impulse response
它可以，因为我们知道可以通过它的脉冲响应描述
and as you've worked out previously
和你以前曾出
in the video course manual for
在视频课程手册
a linear time-invariant system the impulse response
线性时不变系统的脉冲响应
is the derivative love the step response adjusted quickly remind you
是微分爱迅速调整了阶跃响应提醒你
love where that result comes from in essence
爱情里该结果来自于本质
we can consider to linear time-invariant systems and Cascade
我们可以考虑线性时不变系统和级联
wanna differentiator the other the system that we're talking about
想微分器的其他，我们正在谈论的系统
described by
通过描述
the differential equation and step in here
微分方程和步骤，在这里
then generated in polls into our system
然后在投票调查中生成到我们的系统中
and out comes the impulse response well just using the fact that
就出来也只是用事实冲激响应
these are both linear time-invariant systems and they can be cascaded in
这些都是线性时不变系统，他们可以在级联
either order
无论是为了
then means that if we have step response
那么就是说，如果我们有阶跃响应
to our system and that goes through differentiator
我们的系统和经过的区别
what must come out again is the impulse response
什么是必须走出来是脉冲响应
so differentiating the step response we get the impulse response
所以区分阶跃响应我们得到的脉冲响应
here again is the step response as we
这里又是阶跃响应，因为我们
just worked it out this time for you next step if we differentiate
刚做出来这个时候你如果我们区分下一步
we have then since the step response
我们有那么由于阶跃响应
is the product of two terms the derivative a product is the sum
是两个方面的衍生产品，该产品是总和
the derivatives and carrying that algebra through
该衍生工具及附带的代数通过
and using the fact that the derivative the step
和使用该事实衍生物的步骤
is an impulse finally we come down
是一种冲动，我们终于回落
to this statement for the impulse response
本声明的脉冲响应
and then recognizing that this is but I'm
然后认识到这是但我
function times and in polls and we know
函数时间和调查，我们知道
that a time function times in polls takes on
一个时间函数轮询时间发生在
the value at the time that the impulse occurs
在该脉冲发生的时间的值
then this term is simply 0
那么这个词简直是0
and the impulse response then
和脉冲响应，然后
finally is an exponential this for
最后是一个指数本
and this is the peking exponential for a positive
而且这是北京指数为一正
it's a growing exponentially for a negative and
它是一个呈几何级数增长的消极和
recall that as we talked about previously
记得，当我们谈到以前
a system is a linear time-invariant system is stable
一个系统是一个线性时不变系统稳定
if its impulse response is absolutely integral
如果它的冲激响应是绝对不可或缺的
for this particular case this impulse response
对于这个特殊的情况下，该脉冲响应
is absolutely integral provided that
绝对是不可或缺的前提是
the exponential factor a
该指数因子一
is greater than 0
是大于0的
okay so what we've seen then is the
好了，所以我们看到的又是什么
impulse response for system described by a linear constant coefficient
由线性常系数描述的系统冲激响应
differential equation
微分方程
where in addition we will impose causality
这里除了我们将对因果关系
when you're ready in time invariance essentially through the initial
当你准备在时间不变性基本上经历了最初的
conditions
条件
love initial rest
爱最初的休息
now pretty much the same kinds of things happen
现在几乎是同样的事情发生
with difference equations as we've gone through
与差分方程，因为我们通过已经走了
with differential equations in particular
在特定的微分方程
again let me remind you love the form love
让我再提醒你爱的爱的形式
and aunt order when your constant coefficient difference equation
和姑姑订单时，你常系数差分方程
its as I indicate here and
它作为我在此说明，并
again a linear combination this time the late versions of the output equal to a
再次线性组合这时输出的后期版本等于一个
linear combination
线性组合
up the late versions love the input once again
了后期版本热爱输入一次
the difference equation is not
差分方程不
a complete specification the system because we can and to the response
一个完整的规范体系，因为我们可以和响应
any homogeneous solution in other words
换句话说，任何均相溶液
any solution that satisfies the homogeneous equation
满足齐次方程的任何解决方案
in the summer those well also satisfy the original
在夏季的好也满足原
difference equation so if we have
差分方程，所以如果我们有
a particular response that satisfies
一个特定的反应，满足
the difference equation then ending to that
那么差分方程结束到
any response there is a solution to the homogeneous equation
任何回应有一个解决齐次方程
will also be a solution to the total equation
也将是一个溶液的总方程式
the homogeneous solution again is of the form
均相溶液再次的形式为
of a linear combination of exponentials here
指数函数这里的线性组合
we have the homogeneous equation as with
我们有齐次方程与
differential equations we can
微分方程，我们可以
guests or impose solutions for
客人或强加的解决方案
eight times an exponential when we substitute this
八倍的指数，当我们这代
into the homogeneous equation we then end up
入齐次方程，我们再结束
with equation that i've indicated here we recognize again
与我在这里表示式，我们重新认识
there a the amplitude
有一个幅度
and seats at the end
和座椅在年底
this exponential factor cancel out
该指数因子抵消
and so this equation is satisfied
因此该方程是满意
for any values love see
对于任何值热爱看
that satisfy this equation and
满足该方程，并
there are and roots C-one through Z and
有和根的C-1通过Z和
and so finally the form for the homogeneous solution
所以最终的形式为均相溶液
is a linear combination love capital and
是一个线性组合的爱情资本，
exponentials capital and is the order the equation
指数函数首府，也是为了方程式
with each of those exponentials the ample to factor is undetermined
每个这些指数函数的充足到的因素是不确定的
and needs to be determined in some way through
并且需要以某种方式通过确定
the imposition love appropriate
施加适当的爱
initial conditions are boundary conditions
初始条件边界条件
so the general form then
所以一般形式，然后
for the solution to the difference equation
为解决差分方程
is
some with the exponentials plus any particular solution
一些与指数函数加上任何特定的解决方案
its through auxiliary conditions that we determine
通过它，我们确定的辅助条件
these coefficients we have
这些系数我们
and undetermined coefficients and so
和待定系数等等
we require capital and auxiliary conditions
我们需要资金和辅助条件
for example some set values
例如一些设定值
of the output at and this thing instance
在输出端，这件事实例
time
时间
now this
现在这个
was the same as with differential equations in the case a differential
是一样的，与的情况下微分方程的差分
equations we talked about specifying
我们谈到了指定方程
the value of the output and its derivatives and
输出及其衍生物的价值，
there we indicated dead for linearity
我们有死表示为线性
what we required when the arity what we require
我们什么时候需要什么，我们需要的元数
is that the auxiliary conditions 30
是，辅助条件30
and the same thing applies here for the same reason
而同样的道理也适用于这里出于同样的原因
namely if the system is to be linear and the response if there's no input must be
即，如果系统是为线性和响应，如果没有输入必须是
equal to 0
等于0的
in addition what
除了什么
we may want to impose on the system is
我们可能需要对系统性能是
that it be causal and in addition to linear
这是因果关系而除了线性
time-invariant and with that requires again
不随时间变化，并与同样需要
is that it the auxiliary conditions be consistent with
是它的辅助条件是一致
initial rest namely that if
最初的休息即如果
the input is zero prior to some time
输入是零之前一定时间
in the output is zero prior to the same time
在输出为零之前，同时
okay so we've seen a very direct parallel
好了，我们已经看到了非常直接的并行
so far between differential equations
到目前为止微分方程之间
and difference equations
与差分方程
in fact one difference between them dead
其实它们之间的一个区别死
in some sense makes difference equations
在某种意义上使得差分方程
easier to deal with in some situations is dead
更容易处理在某些情况下是死的
in contrast to a differential equation a
相反的差分方程
difference equation if we assume causality
差分方程，如果我们假设的因果关系
in fact is and explicit
其实是和明确的
input-output relationship for the system now let me
为系统的输入输出关系现在让我
show you what I mean
告诉你我是什么意思
let's consider the n-th order difference equation as i've indicated here
让我们考虑n阶差分方程，因为我已经在这里表示
and let's assume that we're imposing causality
让我们假设我们正在实施的因果关系
so there'd the output can only depend
所以会输出只能靠
on prior values at the input and therefore on fire values at the output
对在输入前值，因此起火值在输出
well we can simply rearrange this equation
好，我们可以简单地重新排列这个方程
solving for Y have an the leading term with cable 0
解y有带有线0领先的任期
taking all the other turns over to the right side of the equation
考虑到所有的其他匝转移到右侧的方程
and we then have a workers if equation
然后我们有一个工人，如果方程
namely that an equation expresses the output interns
即一个方程表示的输出实习生
love prior values if the input which is this term
爱前值如果输入的是这个词
and prior values at the output
并且在输出之前的值
and so if in fact we have this equation running
所以如果事实上我们有这个公式运行
then once it started we know how to compute
那么一旦它开始，我们知道如何计算
the output for the next time
接下来的时间，输出
well
好
how do we get started the way we get it started of course
我们如何开始我们得到它开始课程的方式
is through the appropriate said love
通过适当的说爱情
initial conditions are boundary conditions and if for example
初始条件为边界条件，如果例如
we assume initial rest corresponding to a causal when you're time-invariant
我们假设初始静止对应于因果，当你的时间不变
system
系统
then if the input is zero up until sometime
然后，如果输入是零，直至某时
the output must be zero up until that time and Matt in essence
输出必须为零，直到那个时候和马特在本质
helps us get the equation started well let's look at this
帮助我们得到方程开局不错，让我们看看这个
specifically in the context love a
特别是在上下文中的爱情
first-order difference equation so let's take
一阶差分方程所以让我们
a first-order difference equation
一阶差分方程
as i've indicated here
因为我已经在这里表示
and so we have an equation that tells us that why I have and minus eight times
所以我们有一个公式，它告诉我们，为什么我和减号八倍
wider than -1
比-1更宽
is equal to exit
等于退出
now if we want this to correspond to
现在，如果我们希望这对应
a causal linear time-invariant system we
因果线性时不变系统，我们
oppose initial impose initial rest on it we can
最初的反对强加给它，我们可以初步休息
rewrite the first-order difference equation by taking
通过采取重写一阶差分方程
the term involving y ven -1
涉及ŸVEN -1术语
over to the right hand side of the equation
以上等式的右边
right now this gives us a workers if equation
现在这给了我们一个工人，如果方程
that expresses the output interns the input and past values at the output
表示可输出实习生的输入值和过去值在输出
and since we've impose causality
既然我们已经强加因果关系
and if we're talking about a linear time-invariant system
如果我们谈论的是一个线性时不变系统
we can now inquire as to what the impulse responses and we know of course
我们现在可以问，什么的脉冲响应，我们当然知道
that the impulse response
该脉冲响应
charles is everything that we need to know about the system
查尔斯是我们需要了解的一切制度
okay so let's shoes and input which is
好吧让我们的鞋子和输入是
an impulse so the impulse response
一个脉冲，因此脉冲响应
is Beltre van corresponding
Beltre是对应的事
to the exit and appear plus eighty Delta
到出口，并出现加80三角洲
love this should be a chip N -1
爱这应该是一个芯片N-1
and let me just correct that this is a chip N -1
并让我正确的，这是一个芯片N-1
so we have the impulse response as Delta van
所以我们有脉冲响应三角洲面包车
was eight times a Japan -1
是八倍日-1
now from initial rest we know
现在，从最初的其余部分，我们知道
bad since the input namely an impulse is 0 for and less than zero
坏，因为输入即一个脉冲为0和小于零
the impulse response is likewise 0
的脉冲响应是同样0
for and less 0 and now
为少0，现在
let's work out what 80 its well
让我们制定出什么80的好
80 with an equal 0 is
80与平等是0
delta up zero plus eight times
三角洲高达零加八倍
a chip N -1 HRN minus 10
芯片N-1 HRN零下10
and so h0 is equal to 1
等h0为等于1
okay now that we have a chance 0 we can figure at H
现在没事了，我们有机会0我们可以计算为H
one by running this recursive equations
1通过运行这个递推方程
so 8 you've won is
所以8你赢的是
Delta love one which is zero
三角洲爱一个是零
plus eight times h0 which we just figured out as one
加上八次H0，我们只是想出了为一体
so HR one is equal to a and if we carry this through
所以HR 1等于一个，如果我们进行这个过
will have a chip to equal to a squared and
将有一个芯片，等于一个平方和
this will continue on and in fact we can recognize
这将继续，而事实上，我们可以识别
by looking at this and how we would expect these terms to build
通过观察这一点，我们如何期望这些条款来构建
we would see that the impulse response a Japan
我们会看到，脉冲响应日本
in fact -ism form a to the end times
事实上主义形式的结束时间
you have an
你有一个
and we also can recognize then dead
我们也可以识别，然后死了
this corresponds to stable system
这相当于稳定的系统
if and only if the impulse response
当且仅当脉冲响应
which is what we just figured out if and only if the impulse response
这就是我们只是想出了当且仅当脉冲响应
is absolutely so noble and what that will require
绝对是那么高贵，什么是需要
is that the magnitude a the less
是一个数量级的减
okay now we impose causality linear ready in time invariance
现在没事了，我们强加因果线性准备时间不变性
and generated a solution recur simply
并产生一个解决方案，简单地重演
and now of course if we want to generate the more general
现在当然如果我们要生成更一般的
center solutions to this difference equation
中心的解决方案，这个差分方程
we can't do that by adding all of the
我们不能这样做，通过将所有的
homogeneous solutions namely all the solutions to satisfy the homogeneous
齐次解，即所有的解决方案，以满足均匀
equation so
所以方程
here we have the causal linear time-invariant
在这里我们有因果线性时不变
impulse response in fact
事实上冲激响应
with an impulse input all of the possible solutions
带有脉冲输入的所有可能的解决方案
are that impulse response plus
是脉冲响应加
the homogeneous solutions the homogeneous solution is the solution
在均相溶液中的均相溶液是溶液
that satisfies the homogeneous equation
满足齐次方程
that will in general
在一般的意志
believe the form an amplitude factor
相信形式的振幅因子
times an exponential factor and
次指数因子，
if we substitute this into this equation
如果我们这代入这个方程
then we see that the homogeneous
那么我们看到，均匀
equation is satisfied for any values have a
等式成立的任何值有
in any values see that satisfy
在任何值看出，满足
this equation again as we did with differential equations
这个公式再次为我们与微分方程做
the factor Amy cancels out and also in fact I can cancel out is either the N
因素艾米取消了，也其实我可以取消或者是N个
there and seat to the end here
那里的座位到这里结束
and so what we're left with is a statement that tells us
所以我们留下了什么是一个声明，告诉我们
then dead the homogeneous
然后死齐
solution is over for AC to the end
解决方案是通过在AC到端
for any ban you capital A and any value
对于任何禁止你的资本A和任意值
see it satisfies this equation and
看到它满足这个方程，
that values the in particular is the
珍视的，尤其是
people today so the homogeneous solution then
现代人这样的均相溶液，然后
is any exponential this form with any amplitude factor
任何指数这种形式与任何幅度的因素
and so the family of solutions with an impulse
等解决方案与冲动的家庭
input is the solution
输入是解决
corresponding to the system being cause a linear and time-invariant
对应于该系统是造成线性和时间不变
plus the homogeneous sir
再加上齐先生
if
we impose causality Lenny a ready in time invariance
我们强加因果关系莱尼一个现成的时间不变性
on the system then of course that additional
在系统上，然后当然该附加
exponential factor will be 0 in other words capital A
指数因素将是0，换句话说大写A
is 0
okay now in we seen the
还好现在我们看到的
differential equations and difference equations interns
微分方程和差分方程实习生
love
爱
the fact there there are families have solutions
其实有有家庭有解决方案
and in order to get causality Lenny a ready in time
而为了得到因果关系莱尼一个现成的时间
variance requires imposing a particular set initial conditions namely
方差需要施加一组特定的初始条件，即
imposing initial rest on the system
在系统上施加初始其余
let's now look at the difference equation
现在让我们看看差分方程
and then later the differential equation interpreted in block diagrams
再后来在框图差分方程解释
now p the difference equation at
现在P时的差分方程
I just simply repeated here is why I have an
我只是简单地重复在这里，所以我有一个
is accident was a white van -1
是事故是一辆白色面包车-1
where I've taken that the late term
在那里我已经采取的任期后期
over to the right hand side of the equation so in effect
以上等式的右边侧，从而有效
what on imposing on this system is causality
在实施此系统上有什么因果关系
I'm assuming that if I know the past history
我假设，如果我知道过去的历史
the input and the output I can determine
输入和输出能确定
the next value the out
下一个值的列
well we can in fact draw a block diagram
好，我们其实可以画一个框图
represents that equation the equation says
表示方程的方程表示
we take exit and for any given bad you
我们采取退出和任何给定的坏你
a van say n0 whatever bad you were computing the output were
一辆面包车说N0什么不好你计算输出被
we take the input at that time
我们把输入当时
and and to it the factor a
和与它的一个因素
times the output value that we calculated last time so
倍，我们计算出最后一次的输出值，以便
if we have excessive and which is our input
如果我们有过多的，哪些是我们的输入
and if we have why I have and which is our output
如果我们有，为什么我已经和这是我们的输出
we in fact can't get why I have an
我们其实不知道为什么我有一个
by taking the last value why event
通过采取最后的值为什么事件
indicated here by putting why I have an
这里表示通过把为什么我有一个
threw it away multiplying Matt
把它扔掉乘以马特
by the factor
由因子
a
and then Anning that result
然后安宁市的结果
to
the input
输入
and the result the doing that is
和结果的这样做是
why event
为什么事件
so the way this block diagram
这样的方式，这框图
might be interpreted for example as an algorithm is this a
可能被解释为示例作为一个算法是这样一
dead we take exit Van add to it
死者身上汲取凡出口给它添加
eight times the previous value the output that some gives us
8次以前的值的输出，一些给我们
the current value of the output which we then put out of the system
我们随后推出了系统的输出电流值
and also put into a delay element or
并且也放入一个延迟元件或
basically it was stored register to use on the next generation a recursion
基本上它是存储寄存器对下一代使用递归
now how do we get this started well we know that the difference equation
现在我们怎么得到这个开局不错，我们知道，差分方程
requires initial conditions
需要初始条件
and in fact the initial conditions
而事实上初始条件
correspond to what we store
对应于我们存储
in that the late register when this block diagram
在后期的寄存器当这个框图
equation initially starts up
方程最初启动
okay now let's look at
还好现在让我们来看看
this for the case %uh difference equations
本作的情况下，％呃差分方程
more generally
更普遍
so what we said is dead we can calculate the output by
所以我们说是死的，我们可以计算出输出
having previous values that the input
具有先前值的输入
previous values at the output and forming
在输出之前的值，并形成
the appropriate linear combination so
适当的线性组合使
let's just build up the more general block diagram
让我们只建立了更一般的框图
that would correspond to this
这将对应于这
and what it says is that we want to have a mechanism
和它说的是，我们希望有一个机制
restoring past values the input in a mechanism for story past values at the
恢复过去的值输入中的一个机制，故事过去的值
output
产量
and i've indicated that on this figure
我已经表明，在这个图
so far by a chain love
到目前为止由一个链的爱
the layout its indicating
其指示布局
that whatever what
，无论什么
the output each delay is the input
每个延迟是输入输出
delayed by one time it's
延迟一个时​​间很
or or interval and so
或或间隔等
what we see down this chain of the ladies are the late replications
我们看到沿着这条链中的女士们什么是已逝的复制
love the input and what we see
爱的输入和我们所看到的
on the other chain is delayed
在另一链被延迟
replications love the output
复制爱的输出
now the difference equation says that we want to take these
现在的差分方程说，我们要采取这些
and multiply them by the appropriate coefficients
并通过适当的系数相乘
the coefficients in the difference equation and so we can do that
在差分方程，所以我们能做到的系数是
as i've indicated here so
因为我已经在这里表示这样
now we have these delay elements each multiplied
现在我们有了这些延迟单元分别乘以
by the appropriate coefficients on the input and by
通过对输入的相应系数与
appropriate coefficients on the output those are then
这些是则输出相应的系数
songs together and
歌曲一起，
so we now what's on these and what's on these
所以我们现在有什么关于这些的，什么是对这些
after we've some these we want to add
之后我们已经有的这些，我们要添加
those together and there's a factor 1 over 80 that comes in
那些在一起，还有，在一个因子1 80
and that and generates are out
并且生成都出来了
and so this in fact and
所以这实际上与
represents a block diagram which is a general block diagram for implementing
表示一个方框图，它是用于实现总体方框图
war representing near constant coefficient difference
战争占近常系数差异
wage
工资
now if you think about what it means in terms of what's a computer algorithm or
现在，如果你想想这是什么意思在一个什么样的计算机算法或条款
a piece of hardware
一个硬件
in fact this block diagram is a recipe or algorithm for doing the
其实这个框图是一个配方或算法做
implementation
履行
by it's important to
由是很重要的
recognize even at this point dad it's only one
即使在这一点上爸爸承认它只有一个
many possible algorithms or implementations for this difference
许多可能的算法或实现这种差异
wage
工资
just for example
只是举例
I can consider that equation
我可以认为方程
core that block diagram
核心的框图
and here I've redrawn at so
在这里我已经在重新绘制等等
here once again I have the same block diagram that we just saw
在这里我要再次说，我们只是看到了同样的框图
and I can recognize for example
我可以承认，例如
that this in essence corresponds to
这在本质上对应于
to linear time-invariant systems
线性时不变系统
in cascade
在级联
now that assumes of course that my
现在假设，当然，我的
initial conditions are such dad I that the system is in fact
初始条件是这样的爸爸我，该系统是在实
when you're and that in turn requires that we're assuming initial rest namely
当你和这反过来要求我们假定初始即休息
before the input does anything
输入做任何事情
other than 0 there are just zero value stored in the registers
除0以外的有存储在寄存器中只是零值
but assuming that it corresponds to a linear time-invariant system
但假设它对应于一个线性时不变系统
this is a cascade to linear time-invariant systems
这是一个级联线性时不变系统
we know that two linear time-invariant systems can be cascaded
我们知道，两个线性时不变系统可以级联
in either order so in particular I can consider
无论是为了使我特别可以考虑
breaking this cascade here and moving this block
在这里打破这种级联和移动这个块
over to the other side and so let's just
转移到另一边，所以我们只
do that
这样做
and when I do
当我做
I then have
然后，我有
this combination systems
这个组合系统
and of course you can ask what advantage there is to do in at
当然你也可以知道哪些优势有做在中
and the advantage arises because it the fact
和优势的产生是因为它的事实
there'd in this form
有这种形式倒是
exactly what is stored in these delays
什么被存储在这些延迟
is also stored in the still air registers
也被存储在静止的空气中的寄存器
in other words it's this intermediate variable
换句话说，它的这个中间变量
whatever it is down this chain of delays and down this chain of the ladies
不管它是沿着这条链中的延迟和沿着这条链上的淑女
and so in fact I can collapse those delays
所以其实我可以折叠这些延迟
into a single chain of delays and
成一个单一的延迟链和
the network that I'm left with is the network that I indicate
那我留下了网络是我指示网络
I missed you graph where what I've done is to simply collapse that
我错过了你图什么地方我所做的就是简单地崩溃了
double chain of the ladies into a single chain
女士们的双链成单链
the waves
浪
now want to ask well what's the advantage to doing that and the
现在要问还有什么优势，这样做和
advantage
优点
one advantage simply stated is that when you think in terms of an implementation
一个优势简单地说就是当你想在执行方面
of a difference equation
一个差分方程
the lady corresponds to
淑女对应
storage register a memory location and by this
存储寄存器的存储位置，并通过这
by simply using the fact that we can interchange the order in which linear
通过简单地使用这一事实，我们可以交换顺序的线性关系
time-invariant systems are cascaded
时不变系统级联
we can reduce the amount of memory by a factor to
我们可以通过一个因子减少内存量，以
okay now
现在没事了
and essentially similar procedure can also be used for
和基本上相似的过程也可以被用于
differential equations in terms of implementation
在执行方面微分方程
using block diagrams for the interpretation implementations
用框图进行了解读的实现
using like diagrams and let me first do that
使用像图，让我第一次做
rather than in general let me first do it in the in
而不是一般的让我先做到这一点在中
the context love a specific example
上下文爱一个具体的例子
so
let's consider a when your constant coefficient differential equation as
让我们考虑当你常系数微分方程为
i've indicated here
我已经在这里表示
and I have terms on the left side in terms on the right side
我有条款左侧来讲右侧
and with the differential equation
和与差分方程
let's consider taking overturns
让我们来考虑侧翻
over to the right side of the equation except
切换到右侧的方程的除外
for the highest the residue in the output next we
在输出下一个我们的残渣最高
integrate both sides of the equation are so that
结合等式的两侧，使
when we're done we end up with the on the left side of the equation
当我们完成我们最终与在等式的左边
with y ft on the right side of the equation with the appropriate number
与右侧用适当数目的方程y的尺
%uh integrations and so the InterPro equation
％呃集成等的InterPro的方程
that will get is for this example y ft the output is except the
将得到的是这个例子Ÿ英尺的输出是除
plus be the scale factor times the integral
再加上是规模的积分系数乘以
the input and -8 at scale factor times the integral
积分在规模的输入和-8因子倍
the output so to
输出，以便向
form the output in a block diagram turns
形成以框图匝数的输出
we form a linear combination of the input
我们形成输入的线性组合
scaled in to grow the input and a scale
缩放生长的输入和一个标度
integral love the output all of that and it together
积分爱情输出所有这一切和它在一起
so we need in addition to
所以我们需要在除了
the input we need the integral
我们需要的积分输入
love the input and so this box indicates an integrator
爱的输入，所以此框表示一个积分
in addition to the output we need
除了我们所需要的输出
the integral the output and now
积分的输出与现在
to for why ft we
以为什么英尺我们
multiply the integrated in play
乘集成在玩
by the scale factor B and
由比例因子B和
and back to exit C
再回到C出口
and retake the integrated output multiplied by Minas de
并夺回集成输出乘以米纳斯日
and and to that
并与该
the result are the previous addition
其结果是除了以前
and according to the integral equation then that forms
并根据该积分方程则该表格
the output
输出
so just as we did with the difference equation
所以就像我们与差分方程做
we've converted the differential equation to
我们已经转换的差分方程
an integral equation and we have a block diagram for very similar
一个积分方程，我们有非常相似的框图
to what we had in the case the difference equation now the initial
我们曾经拥有的情况下，差分方程现在初步
conditions of course
当然条件
are tied up and again how these integrators
绑起来，再怎么这些集成商
are initialized assuming that we impose initial rest on the system
初始化假设我们在系统上施加初始休息
weekend thinkers the overall system is a linear time-invariant system
周末思想家整个系统是一个线性时不变系统
and it's a cascade one linear time-invariant system with the second
这是一个级联一个线性时不变系统与第二
so we can in fact
所以我们其实是可以
break this
打破这种
and consider interchanging the order in which these two systems a cascade
并考虑互换的顺序这两个系统的级联
and so i've indicated that down below here
所以我已经指出，向下跌破这里
I've simply taken the top block diagram
我简直到了顶部框图
interchange the order in which the to
交换的顺序来的
systems are cascaded and
系统级联和
here again we can ask what the advantages to this
在这里，我们再次可以问什么优势，这
as opposed to the previous one and what you can see
相对于前一个，你可以看到什么
just as we saw with the difference equation is that
正如我们看到的差分方程是
now the integrators both integrators
现在集成两个集成
are integrating the same thing in particular
正在将同样的事情，尤其
the input to this integrator and the input
输入至该积分器和该输入
to this integrator are identical so in fact
这个积分是相同的所以其实
rather than using this one we can simply tap of
而不是使用这一块，我们可以简单地挖掘
from here we can in fact remove this integrator
从这里我们其实可以消除这种集成
break this connection
打破这种连接
and happy and at this point and so
和快乐，在这一点上，所以
what we've done and by interchange in the order in which the systems are
我们已经在该系统是为了完成和交流
cascaded
级联
is reduced the implementation to the implementation
被减少的实施，实施
with a single integrated very much similar to
用一个单一的集成非常相似的
what we talked about in the case the difference wage
我们的情况下谈到了工资差异
now let's just again with the integral equation
现在就让我们再次与积分方程
way the differential equation looked at
这样的微分方程看着
this somewhat more generally again
这个较为普遍再次
if we take the differential equation the general differential equation
如果我们把微分方程的一般微分方程
integrated a sufficient number of times to convert it to an integral equation
集成的足够次数，将它转换为一个积分方程
we would then have this cascaded systems
那么我们将有这个级联系统
and again if we assume initial rest
并再次，如果我们假设初始休息
so that these are both linear time-invariant systems
所以，这些都是线性时不变系统
we can interchange the order in which they are cascaded
我们可以交换它们被级联的顺序
namely take the second system and
即以第二个系统和
move it
移动
to proceed the first system
进行第一系统
and then we recognize is that the input to this change
然后我们承认的是，输入到该变化
integrators and this change integrators is exactly the same
集成商和这种变化集成是完全一样的
and so in fact we can collapse these together
所以实际上我们可以一起折叠这些
using only one change integrators and the system
只使用一个变化集成商和系统
there we're left with then is system
有我们留下了然后就是系统
that looks as i've indicated here so we have
看起来就像我在这里表示，所以我们有
now just a single chain integrators
现在只是一个单链整合
is that a the two sets in
是，两组中
so we've seen that the situation is very similar here as it was in the case the
因此，我们已经看到，这种情况是非常相似的在这里，因为它是在情况下，
difference equation
差分方程
again why do we want to cut the number integrators in half
又为什么我们要削减的数量集成了一半
well one reason is because integrators in effect represent hardware
还有一个原因是因为在效果整合代表的硬件
and if we use half as much if we have half as many integrators
如果我们用一半多，如果我们有一半多的集成商
then using half as much hard
然后用一半的硬
okay well let me just conclude by summarizing
还好还有让我通过总结得出结论
a number of points I indicated at the beginning
数点我显示在开头
that linear constant coefficient differential equations a difference
该线性常系数微分方程的差别
equations
方程
will play an important role as linear time-invariant systems
将扮演线性时不变系统的重要作用
throughout this coursing throughout the center lectures
贯穿整个中心的讲座这个窃喜
I also stress
我也紧张
the fact that differential or difference equations
事实上，差分或差分方程
by themselves are not a complete specification
本身并不是一个完整的规范
the system because of the fact that we can and
因为事实上的系统，我们可以和
to any solution a homogeneous
任何解决方案均匀
I do we specify the appropriate initial conditions
我我们指定适当的初始条件
to ensure how do we specify the appropriate initial conditions to ensure
以确保我们如何指定适当的初始条件，以确保
that the system
该系统
is linear and time-invariant well
是线性时不变以及
the auxiliary information namely the initial conditions
的辅助信息，即初始条件
dissociated with the system
离解与系统
be causal linear and time-invariant
是因果线性时不变
are the conditions of initial rest
是的初始静止的条件
and in fact for most of the cores
而实际上大多数的芯
what will be interested in systems that are in fact cause a linear and
这将是感兴趣的是，事实上造成线性系统和
time-invariant
时不变
and so we will in fact be assuming initial rest conditions
所以我们实际上将在假定初始条件休息
now
现在
as I also indicated their are
我也表示，他们顷
a variety of efficient procedures for solving differential
各种有效的程序求解微分
and difference equations that we haven't yet address and
与差分方程，我们还没有解决和
beginning with the next set of lectures will be talking about
与下一组讲座开始将谈论
for EA transform and much later in the course
对EA变换和多后面的课程
what's referred to as the apostrophe its form for continuous-time
什么被称为单引号其形式为连续时间
and sea transport for discrete-time and what we'll see
和海上运输为离散时间，我们会看到
is that with the Fourier transform in later with the apostasy transform
是与傅里叶变换后与叛教变换
will have a number love efficient and very useful ways
将有一批热爱高效和非常有用的方法
%uh generating the solution for
％嗯产生用于解
differential and difference equations this under the assumption that the
的假设下微分和差分方程这使
system is causal
系统是因果
when you're in time very
当你在非常时刻
also will see in addition to the block diagram implementations
也将除了方框图实现见
the systems that we talked about so far
我们说了这么远的系统
we'll see another a number of other useful
我们会看到另一个一些其他有用的
implementations that exploit a variety of properties associated with
即利用各种性能的实现相关联
Korean past thank you
韩国过去谢谢